[mysterious atmospheric music playing]
[woman panting]
[music becomes suspenseful]
[silence falls]
[eerie piano music rises]
THE SECRET WOMAN
2 YEARS LATER
[bells tolling]
BASED ON ANNA EKBERG'SDEN
HEMMELIGE KVINDE
[music becomes gentle]
[man] Have you checked the nets yet? Good.
-[woman] Hi!
-[man] Ah, it's the Danish girl.
[boy] Morning, Louise.
-Here you go.
-[gasps] Wow!
Lovely.
Wow.
Tell me, how's your mum?
-Better.
-Yeah?
Well, as soon as she's well enough,
come for some hot chocolate at the café.
-Okay?
-Okay.
[both chuckling]
[mysterious music playing]
Balder?
-Eight hundred kroner?
-Yep.
-[Louise] Say hi to your mum.
-[boy] Sure.
[Balder] See you soon.
[gentle music playing]
-[Louise] Morning.
-Hi.
[straining] Oi.
All right, what do we have here?
[gasps] Oh, perfect!
-Huh?
-Oh, lovely!
-[laughs] Let's put crab on our specials.
-Uh-huh.
-Okay. Thanks.
-I'll put them in the kitchen.
CRIME SCENE DO NOT CROSS
SERIAL KILLERS
A COMPLETE GUIDE
TO POLICE PROCEDURE
[Louise] Hmm.
[Louise] Good morning.
-Hi.
-Late night?
[breathy chuckle]
Did I wake you?
-No. No, not at all.
-Are you sure?
Mm.
Get any writing done?
Or did you get distracted?
[chuckles] I don't know what to say.
-The pyramids again?
-No.
-No? [chuckles]
-[chuckles]
It was worse than that, in fact.
I went down a… a rabbit hole
with Mount Kailash, right.
It's a sacred mountain in Tibet actually.
-Mm-hmm.
-There are lots of stories…
about all these
temporal distortion things.
-[laughs] I love you, you nerd!
-There's more to it.
-[laughs] Mm.
-There are conspiracy theories…
-[man] Seriously.
-[foghorn blaring]
[tour guide] We're now arriving
at the island of Tysnes.
A small island
with only 2,400 inhabitants,
but one with deep roots in Norse history.
Around the island you will find sites
of great cultural
and historical importance.
[camera shutter clicking]
[Louise] Let me know
if you need anything. [chuckles]
Thank you, Maria.
-You're welcome. Say hi to your folks.
-Yeah, I will.
-See you.
-[boy] Bye.
[Louise chuckles]
-[Maria] Louise?
-Mm?
That guy sitting there
won't stop staring at you.
But you are gorgeous,
so I don't blame him.
[both chuckle]
Ooh, well he's coming over here.
-Oh, great.
-Mm.
Helene?
It's me, Peter.
We, uh, worked at the same company.
Uh, sorry, but I'm not Helene.
-Hmm… What do you mean?
-[Louise] My name's Louise.
This is me.
Louise Andersen.
-My apologies.
-No worries at all.
[Peter] You must have a doppelgänger.
[woman] Congratulations
to Joachim and Louise. Cheers.
Here we go. Dinner's served!
-[man] Ooh.
-[Maria] Enjoy.
[glass clinking for attention]
[chuckles] Time for me
to make a speech, I'm afraid.
Okay. Um, yeah.
We are engaged. She said yes.
I'm pleased to say, finally.
Um, it's a very cheap ring, I'm afraid.
[group chuckling]
[man] We've been here
almost two years now.
And I've never felt more at home as,
um, I do here with you.
Aw, you're welcome.
[man] Thank you.
Um, Louise…
Um, you are a magical person.
-Mysterious. And magical.
-[all chuckling]
And I feel like I've spent
a lot of time thinking about all of my…
silly, uh, little books
and the never-ending mountain
of boring research. Uh…
[all chuckling]
As if that was all that mattered.
But not any more.
You bring meaning to my life.
Every day.
And I adore you.
I love you.
[group cheering]
Right, time for you to raise your glass.
To both of you, and love.
-Thank you.
-[woman] Cheers, everyone!
-[door knocking]
[crockery clinking]
-[man] Who is it?
-Him again?
Who?
Uh, there was a Danish man at the café
who wouldn't stop staring at Louise today.
He thought I was someone he knew, but…
Oh, yeah?
I'd rather not talk to him again.
I'll make sure he gets the message.
[clears throat]
[man] Yes?
Hi. I'd like to speak to Helene.
Yeah, well, sorry, there's no one
called Helene here, I'm afraid.
[Peter] Look, I have something
very important to tell her.
It's about her past, okay?
[mysterious music playing]
As I said you're, uh…
You're barking up the wrong tree,
I would say. So…
Okay.
He was obnoxious.
-[Louise] Yes.
-And you've never seen the guy before?
[inhales] I don't think. Um…
I don't remember seeing him before, um…
I don't think so, but, erm…
Hey. What is it?
Is there something
that's coming back to you?
Nothing, he just made me…
[inhales deeply]
…scared.
[emotional string music playing]
[man] Louise, If he's somehow managed
to jog your memory…
If you're starting to remember…
you can tell me. We'll figure things out.
Yeah.
Thank you.
-Let's sleep now.
-Mm.
[thunder rumbling]
[mysterious music playing]
[rain pattering]
[thunder rumbling]
[distorted twinkling]
[child] Wow.
[mysterious music ticking]
I'VE GONE TO THE MAINLAND. I'LL BE BACK
ON THE LAST FERRY THIS AFTERNOON.
I LOVE YOU!
[policewoman] Okay, Louise. You've come
because you're unsure of your identity?
[Louise] Yes.
I see. And your file says that
just over two years ago,
you were found unconscious at the harbour?
Yes. Well, um, I was on a ship,
when it came into the harbour.
And you had, uh, serious injuries?
Yeah. Yeah, to my neck,
my head, an arm, and my ribs.
And you've no idea how you managed
to board the ship, is what it says here?
No.
[Louise] I was in hospital
for a long time.
Um…
And the doctors
then diagnosed me with amnesia.
Then how did the doctors know
who you were?
I still had my bag
with a few belongings and my ID.
So they told me who I was.
-[policewoman] Louise Andersen?
-Yeah.
And so the Danish police just accepted
the fact that you were Louise Andersen?
Yes, they did, because
I said that they were right.
I told them I was Louise
and my memories were coming back to me.
And were they?
No, um, I had no idea who I was.
Why didn't you say that?
Because… It's hard to explain,
but I was afraid.
It's frightening not to know who you are…
I guess I hoped that I was her.
And you left it at that?
No. I searched for myself online.
There was nothing though.
-Nothing?
-There are many Louise Andersens.
And the police?
No one contacted family or anything?
Well, I didn't have one.
No next of kin?
No. It turned out
I'd… I'd lived a… a hard life.
The only records the police had of me were
a couple of arrests in Copenhagen for…
for prostitution.
I… I have a feeling
I must've been on the run back then.
So I came here
to find out who I am and what happened.
Right.
We'll do a DNA test.
[ominous music playing]
[policewoman] Your real name
is Helene Söderberg.
You disappeared
from your family in Denmark
just over two years ago.
The Danish police
have been looking for you ever since.
A lot of people have been looking for you.
And you're married.
You have a son.
A son?
-[woman] Hi. Joachim Bjørndal? Iben Rask.
-[Joachim] Hi. Yes.
Can you explain it again?
[Iben] Because she had an ID
when she was found,
unfortunately they didn't investigate
the matter any further.
And she confirmed to them
that she was Louise Andersen.
[Joachim sighs]
And where… Where is Louise?
Oh, wait.
I guess she isn't Louise, is she?
No. Helene's now in the care
of the crisis team.
You can see her if you like,
but just to reiterate, Joachim…
It's definitely her.
The DNA test proved it.
We contacted the Danish police
and it's been verified.
And we've also notified
her family in Denmark.
Her family?
[mysterious music playing]
Apologies. A shorter last name
would've made life easier.
[all chuckle]
[woman] Mr. Söderberg? Sorry to interrupt.
-Yes?
-Um, it's urgent I'm afraid.
[Söderberg] Ah. Excuse me.
[woman] He'll be right back.
Yes?
[mysterious music intensifies]
[sighs]
Did you speak to the police?
Yeah. They've explained it all to me, so…
It'll be okay.
I think Helene's a beautiful name.
[both chuckle softly]
Well, we'll work through it.
I must go and meet them.
[Joachim] Yeah.
I have a child.
I'm someone's mother.
I have to go to Denmark
and figure out what happened.
You're right. Mm.
I understand.
But you know this doesn't change anything.
You and I are getting married.
[dramatic music playing]
WELCOME TO COPENHAGEN
[man] Now then. Are you excited?
I am, yeah.
[man] Mm?
You look wonderful.
-[man] Let me see you.
-Okay.
You take it easy. Don't blame her.
You know she's been through
a terrible ordeal.
I'm sure it must be hard for her.
[driver] We're here, Mrs Söderberg.
[boy] Is that her?
Yes. I presume.
[nervous breathing]
Hi.
-Hi.
-[woman] Welcome.
[man] Uh, don't you want to say hi
to your mother, Alexander?
You wanna say hi?
-[man] Don't you want to say hello?
-[woman] Hmm?
-[man] Alexander?
-[woman] I'll go after him.
Right. Um, this is my mother.
Yeah.
Caroline.
It is so good to have you home again.
-[man] Uh, will you go check on him?
-[woman] Of course.
I'm sure he'll come around.
And then there's me, uh… I'm Edmund.
[both chuckle]
-Um…
-I guessed you… you were.
-It's… It's all a… a bit awkward.
-Yes.
[both chuckle nervously]
[Edmund] Mm.
You'll come inside?
Yes. [chuckles] Okay.
I can take your things.
Thanks.
Go on in.
["Piano Sonata in A Minor, K. 310: II"
by Mozart playing]
This is your childhood home.
You grew up here with your father.
And that's you and him.
[Edmund] This is the piano room.
You used to play here as a child.
[sighs] And in here
was your father's study.
[Edmund] You don't recognise anything?
[Helene] No, not really.
Well, um, they said to expect that.
I had hoped that
when you saw Alexander and me,
you know, things might begin to…
[inhales] …come back.
Well, the psychologists hope so.
I hope so too.
[Helene] Thank you.
What happened when I disappeared?
Just before you vanished,
your father passed.
The man hadn't been well at all.
He went downhill very rapidly and you…
you took care of him.
But it was very intense.
His passing brought out
a sort of dark bleakness in you.
You had been on medications…
And I think it's possible
you stopped taking them.
So you were just spiralling.
And then you disappeared.
I spent months looking for you.
But in all my searching,
I never had the thought to look abroad,
which I will always regret.
Helene, this isn't easy
for me to say, but…
In the end I told myself
that you had ended it all.
It was an option you'd mentioned before.
[ominous music playing]
Oh… [exhales] I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to bring all this up.
It wasn't my intention
to drag up all that…
-Uh…
-No, I was the one asking, don't worry.
Sorry.
Do you… Do you think I could, um…
maybe talk to him?
Oh yes, sure. Uh, right.
Up the stairs, first door on your right.
-Thanks.
-Yeah.
[door knocking]
[Helene] Alexander?
[dreamy atmospheric music playing]
You don't remember me?
I will, eventually.
Did you miss me?
Yeah. I did, in my heart.
I'm here now.
I won't go away again. Okay?
Mm.
[Alexander trembling]
-[softly] Oh, Alexander…
-[Alexander sobs softly]
You never call me Alexander.
[Helene] Then what do I call you?
You really don't know it?
[exhales] I'm trying.
[Helene] Duckling.
Duckling.
Of course.
[tense music playing]
[dial tone ringing]
[Iben] Hi, this is Iben Rask.
Hi, hi. It's Joachim.
I recently spoke to you at the hospital.
Oh, hi, Joachim.
-[Joachim] Hello.
-How is everything?
[Joachim] I just find it a bit strange.
Something's not right.
[Iben] Is that
the crime writer in you talking?
No, I mean… Have you tried looking up
her name online? Helene Söderberg?
Yes, I did try that.
[Joachim] And what did you find?
-Yeah, I didn't find too much.
-[Joachim] Exactly. Nothing.
[Joachim] I've been searching
for four hours and not a thing.
No social media, nothing. It's odd.
[Iben] Yeah, I have to say,
I don't disagree with you there.
And then there's her new identity…
This other woman's stolen identity…
The real Louise.
What about her? Where is she?
Look, her case has already gone over
to the Danish police.
So is there…
A contact, or someone
I could speak to over there?
[Iben] Yes.
Your grandma's on her way.
Good night.
[Alexander] Good night.
[ominous music playing]
[distorted twinkling]
[man groans and coughs]
[Edmund] Helene?
[birds tweeting]
Is he sleeping?
No.
But he let me read to him.
Your mother's with him now
until he falls asleep.
Right.
He's been a little more, um…
Mm… Anxious after you vanished.
Um, this wine…
It's one of your favourites.
Well it used to be a favourite.
[Helene chuckles softly] Ah.
[Edmund] A toast.
A toast.
[Helene chuckles]
[Edmund] Do you like it?
Mm.
Um, how long have we been married?
[laughs]
Sorry, they probably said already
but it's such a blur.
-[Edmund] It's eight years now.
-Woah.
And how did we meet each other?
I worked in your father's business,
uh, and that's where we both worked.
And well now… we run the company.
We're both on the board of directors.
In, um, shipping… I've been told?
Yeah, shipping.
[inhales] We are the fourth-largest
shipping firm in the North.
[chuckles]
[inhales]
-So, what do I do there?
-[Edmund laughs]
Uh… Um…
You were our CFO.
You were very good. Very sharp.
-So, in finance?
-[Edmund] Yes.
-That's what I did?
-[Edmund] Mm-hmm.
-[Helene] I run a café on the island.
-Mm.
That's why business and accounting came
really easily to me, I suppose.
-Well, there you go.
-Mm.
Um, I don't run it alone. The café. I…
[inhales deeply]
I run it with my boyfriend.
Well, my fiancé.
Yep, I know. Um… yeah.
Joachim.
Yeah.
I see that you're um…
You're wearing his ring?
Yes. Do you mind?
I'm just glad you're back home again.
And I'm glad
that Alexander has his mother back.
Um, and then, then rest
we'll just make work somehow, right?
-Yeah.
-[Edmund] But…
I'd really like to show you something.
Bring your wine.
-Come on.
-Okay. [chuckles softly]
[Edmund] It's a small film we had made
for you for your birthday a few years ago.
It's your story.
-Hi!
-[man] Hi.
[both laughing]
[young Helene] I'm flying!
[Edmund] You grew up here with your father
after your mother died.
She got cancer, sadly, when, um…
when you were very young.
But your father adored you,
and he gave you everything you wanted.
[chuckling]
[Edmund] And you two were inseparable.
And you and I, we… we met at work.
Well, I…
I was so intimidated by you.
The boss's beautiful daughter.
[chuckles softly]
[chuckles]
[Edmund] But I won you over.
And we got married.
We were madly in love.
Nothing could keep us apart.
[people cheering on film]
[chuckles]
[Helene] Feel it, he's kicking now!
[Edmund] And then our family was complete
when Alexander came along.
We were so happy.
[Edmund chuckles softly]
[Helene on film]
His little hands, his nose…
[door knocking]
Helene, you'll sleep
in the master bedroom, all right?
And I'll make up a guest room for Edmund.
I think it's the best option.
Wait, Caroline?
Yes?
Thank you for taking care of Alexander.
Oh, but of course.
It's truly been a joy.
He's honestly such a delight.
[chuckles softly]
And, um…
Was I a good mother?
[Caroline] You were just as you should be.
You listened to him. You adored him.
It’s just hard to believe
that I forgot about him.
Or that I'd forget
giving birth to my child.
You really don't remember anything?
-A few things here and there.
-[Caroline] Well, there you go.
Your head's playing tricks on you
but your heart remembered him.
[Caroline] Don't blame yourself.
You're here now.
[Caroline] Sleep well.
You too.
[sighs]
[dial tone ringing]
[Joachim] Hi.
Hi.
Go on. What's going on?
It's… intense.
[Joachim] I can imagine.
But what's it like there?
Are they… nice? Looking after you?
[Helene] It's… really big here.
[chuckles softly] And grand.
They seem good. And there's Alexander.
Yeah.
But have you found out
any more answers, or information?
That's why you went to Denmark, isn't it?
Yeah. No, right now,
I'm just trying to navigate it all.
[Joachim] Right, but what happened
when you disappeared?
You have to find out how you ended up
on that ship to Norway.
Joachim, I…
[sighs]
It will have to wait.
I can't handle anymore right now.
I'm going to need some more time, okay?
Yeah, all right.
I love you.
[Helene] I'll be in touch, okay? Bye.
[electronic suspenseful music playing]
-[Alexander] Bye, Grandma.
-[Caroline] Bye, darling. Bye.
See you.
[Alexander] Hi, David.
[David] Hi, Alexander.
Look, this is my mum.
-What's your name?
-I'm Helene.
She's been home for two days.
-Hi! Hello.
-Ooh.
Hello there! Your friends?
-[boy] Have you been to the school before?
-[Helene] No, I haven't.
-[boy] I've been to Norway too.
-Okay.
It's so beautiful.
-[bell ringing]
-Bye, Mum.
All right, duckling. Have a good day.
Okay, sweetheart?
-[Helene] See you.
-[Alexander] Have a nice day, Mum!
Are you sure you're ready, Helene?
[Helene sighs] Yeah. I'm hoping
it will help me remember.
[Edmund] Okay.
[man 1] Hi, Helene. I'm glad you're back.
Hmm. Thanks.
-[man 2] Good morning.
-Good morning.
Hi, Helene. So good to see you again.
-Thanks.
Beautiful flowers.
[Peter chatting indistinctly]
[Edmund] Are you okay?
Uh… That man… The one over there
looks a lot like the man who…
saw me in Norway.
Oh, well it is him.
He works in our compliance department.
He was on holiday in Norway
when he saw you. Luckily for us.
Welcome back, Helene.
Thank you.
[intense music playing]
[officer] This is the last known photo
of Louise Andersen.
We sent that photo to the Norwegian police
and they identified her, so…
Well, that was that.
Okay, but who is she, right?
I mean, who is Louise Andersen?
We have very little on Louise Andersen
other than she was a prostitute.
We've listed her as missing,
but people in that world
tend to disappear.
It's just… do you think they look alike?
Do you think Helene and Louise look alike?
-I'd say a little.
-[Joachim] Oh.
Height, hair colour, eye colour.
But most importantly, the officers
involved had no reason to suspect
that the woman on the ID wasn't her
when they found her.
Okay. But so, Helene Söderberg, then…
Why didn't you do a bigger search
when she went missing?
Well, there weren't many leads.
And our information suggested that
she had committed suicide.
What information?
A history of mental illness.
Helene Söderberg
was suffering from psychosis
when she disappeared. Severe psychosis.
Hello, Mrs Söderberg.
So, Edmund showed you to your old office?
[Helene] Yes.
[both chuckle softly]
Ingrid.
You don't recognise me?
No, sorry.
Well… Well,
I suppose we'll just start over.
Ingrid Jensen.
I was your secretary before.
And you also worked for my father?
Yes. Until he fell sick and then you…
then you took over.
Uh, so…
I'm so sorry, they said that if we were…
if we were talking of the past,
then we must be careful with it.
Oh, please don't worry, it's no problem.
I'm actually trying to remember
as much as possible.
Mm.
Ah, well in that case…
Why don't you look in here.
It's an anniversary book celebrating
the first ten years of the company.
[Helene] Okay.
SÖDERBERG SHIPPING
1967-1977
[distorted rumbling]
[both laughing]
[Ingrid] Well, I've brought you
a little of everything.
Annual reports and financial statements.
Don't worry, you won't need
to approve anything here.
It's just to give you an idea.
We'll ease you back in.
-[Ingrid] The first pages are…
-The management figures.
That's correct.
I see you remember a few things, huh?
[chuckles softly] Yeah.
[intense electronic music playing]
POLICE
WANTED AND MISSING PERSONS
MISSING SINCE 2024.
LAST SEEN AROUND HALMTORVET
MISSING SINCE 2024
LOUISE ANDERSEN:
SLENDER BUILD, LONG DARK HAIR
TRANSPORT AND LOGISTICS LEADER
WHO ARE WE?
HISTORY
AKSEL SÖDERBERG FOUNDED SÖDERBERG SHIPPING
IN 1967.
IMAGES
NO RESULTS FOR YOUR SEARCH
Hi. Um, do you have any articles
featuring… these keywords?
[librarian] Let me look.
-[Joachim] Nothing?
-No, no results, sorry.
Do you hold originals here?
I'll see what I can find.
-Thanks, I'll wait.
-You're welcome.
-[Alexander] Come get me!
-[both chuckling]
-[Helene] Go!
[Helene] Come here, you!
[Helene] Right.
[Alexander shouting indistinctly]
-[laughing]
-[Helene] Gotcha!
[Alexander chuckling]
-[sighs]
-[Caroline chuckles]
-No, no, no. Stop!
-[Alexander laughs] You're it!
[Caroline] Oh, Alexander.
-[Alexander] Ready?
-[Helene] We're ready.
-Ready?
-[both] Yes.
-[Helene] You got it? Oh, it's mine.
-[Alexander grunts]
-[Alexander laughs]
-[Helene laughs] We got him!
-[Helene] You got him!
-Come on, Dad.
-[Helene] We got him.
-No!
-[Alexander] Yeah, we did!
-Watch out! He's up!
-[grunts]
-[phone ringing]
-[Alexander] Yeah!
-[Helene cheers] Well done.
-[Edmund] Hold on, hold on, hold on.
-High five!
-[Alexander] Yeah. [chuckles]
-Nice work. [chuckles]
Uh, I need to get this.
[Alexander] No, Dad…
-[Edmund] Hello?
-[Alexander groans]
[Helene] Your shoelace is untied.
-You're good at tennis.
-[Alexander] Thanks.
[Alexander] Are you still mad at Dad?
Mad how?
You screamed at him
right before you disappeared.
You were there?
Yes. It was at night.
Look, parents do argue.
I'm sure there was no need to worry.
[sighs] You were arguing over me.
None of this is your fault.
You know that?
Okay.
[gentle music playing]
[Helene] Mm. Can I taste it?
[Edmund] Mm-hmm. Try it.
-[Edmund] Delicious, isn't it?
-Mm.
[Edmund] I made you this
on our very first date.
[Helene] Mm.
[door knocking]
[breathes deeply]
[Edmund sighs]
I've missed you, Helene.
[sombre string music playing]
[music intensifies]
[Helene] I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
[music steadies]
I'm sorry.
-I… I didn't mean…
-No, no, it's all right.
You aren't ready. It's fine.
[sighs]
[thunder rumbling]
[distorted rumbling]
[Aksel struggling]
[mumbling] Come here.
[inhales deeply]
[eerie piano music playing]
[distant knocking]
[distant commotion]
[rumbling becomes closer]
[ominous music intensifies]
[creaking]
[window creaks]
[distorted rumbling]
[laboured breathing]
Listen. It's important.
-Helene? All okay?
-[gasps]
[sighs] Yeah.
You should be asleep.
My father was up here, wasn't he?
He moved to the tower room
when he got sick.
He wanted a view of the forest.
You said it soothed him.
Do you know…
What he said to me, at the end?
I mean, right before he died?
No, I don't know, my dear.
I didn't know your father all that well.
SUSPICIOUS DEATH
DIED IN HIS OWN HOME
-[officer] Where did you get these?
-National Library.
[officer] Mm-hmm.
All the digital archives were erased.
Which is a bit weird, don't you think?
So I had to make copies
from the actual newspapers.
[inhales deeply] Right.
And how can I help, then?
Well, I want to know
if you ever looked into that?
What exactly?
About… [laughs awkwardly]
…Helen's father. The way he died.
Well, it says he was found dead at home.
We looked into it,
but concluded that it was an accident.
There's no more to that case.
Yeah, but I have more evidence.
Louise… Um, Helene… [sighs]
Helene was found aboard a ship.
This ship here.
Did any of you look into
how she came to be aboard that ship?
[scoffs] You mean how she got on board
a Norwegian ship several years ago?
[sighs] There's no way I could know that.
No, I understand that, but…
I can feel it. There's more going on.
I know it. So will you help me?
I expect she boarded
from one of the harbours along its route.
If I were you, I'd locate the ship's log
and then you can check the route it took.
There's nothing else we can do.
[ominous electronic music rises, fades]
[Alexander] Ten, thirty…
What about that one? What is it?
Alexander, we need to go.
Can you get ready?
[Alexander] Okay.
Yeah. Off you go.
Good morning.
I'll check on him.
Your mother seems so wonderful, Edmund.
I'm glad she was with Alexander
while I was away.
[Edmund] Yes.
[Helene] By the way, I was thinking…
We haven't really spoken about
my father, you know?
How he died.
You and Alexander were alone
in the house that day.
And no one really knows what happened.
But we think he might have been trying
to leave his room
and he fell… down the stairs.
[gasps]
So it was me who found him or…?
[Edmund] Yes.
I've been withholding the details.
It was violently traumatising for you.
My darling, I don't want you to go back
to that dark place again.
[ominous music playing]
OUR EMPLOYEES PHOTOGRAPHED
IN FRONT OF THE OFFICES ON WILDERS STREET
Ingrid, how come there's pages missing?
Oh. No idea.
I've got another copy at home
from when I first began working here.
I can see if they're in there,
if you'd like?
That would be great. Thank you.
-Um, Ingrid?
-Yeah?
What was I doing before I disappeared?
Uh… Uh…
Uh… Oh, I think it's best if you…
talk to your husband about it, yes?
It's only that I'd really like to know…
your view of what… what happened.
Uh, well…
[inhales] I can only really tell you
what you said to me.
Mm-hmm.
Well, he tried to speak to you about
something important right before he died.
On his deathbed, he drifted
in and out of consciousness, so…
he would forget
what he'd already said to you,
and so he ran out of time
to tell you it all.
[mysterious music playing]
Hmm.
And then right before you vanished…
it seemed like you were obsessed.
How? What… What was I doing?
You were convinced that he had…
a warning, a confession.
That there was something
you needed to know before he died
and you took over the company.
Then, after he passed,
you combed through everything here.
Contracts, transactions, every client,
all of the routes. I mean it.
All of it. You became more and more…
It pains me to say it, but…
you seemed manic, to tell the truth.
You were working day and night.
And what about Edmund?
[sighs] Edmund, he…
He tried to ease your mind.
Reassure you it was okay.
So that's why I disappeared.
Uh… Sorry, I…
I discovered something.
His death wasn't why I broke down.
I can only say what I saw.
Yes.
[distorted rumbling]
[gasps]
Ingrid, I'd like to know precisely what
I was doing before I disappeared.
What I was working on and who I met with.
Yes. I'll find your old diary.
Thanks.
[Ingrid] I do remember one thing though.
Your last meeting was with the bank.
You were saying
that meeting was important to you…
Yes, I remember finding it strange
that you weren't meeting with
Söderberg's branch
who we dealt with normally.
[Helene] Okay.
Okay. Could you find the name of the bank,
and my calendar?
[Ingrid] Of course.
[footsteps retreating]
-[bank teller] Mrs Söderberg?
-Hi.
[bank teller] It's been a while.
Good to see you again.
Likewise.
So, how can we help you today?
-When I last was here, um…
-Mm.
What did I say to you?
Uh, do you mean when you set up
your safe-deposit box?
Yeah. That time.
Yeah, what exactly was our agreement?
[bank teller] Well,
there was no agreement as such.
You just set up a safe-deposit box.
And you didn't want your husband to know.
That was it, yeah.
[mysterious music playing]
PRENUPTIAL AGREEMENT
[phone ringing]
-[Helene] Yes, Ingrid?
-[Ingrid] I found your old calendar.
And?
In the days before you disappeared,
you had a meeting
with someone called Elisabeth Fauerskov.
-Does that ring a bell?
-Not at all.
She was the CEO of
one of our sub-contractors, JM Shipping.
And I believe she knew your husband.
Okay?
-Anyway, I'm sending you her details now.
-Okay. Thanks for that.
-Right, bye.
-Thank you.
[notification chimes]
[dial tone ringing]
-[Elisabeth] Elisabeth Fauerskov.
-Hi, Elisabeth. I am Helene Söderberg.
-I'm calling to speak…
-I… I don't want to talk to you.
-Don't contact me.
-[call disconnects]
[scoffs]
[dial tone ringing]
[call disconnects]
[mysterious music playing]
[distorted rumbling]
SHIP ROUTE INFO
FYKSESUND BRIDGE
[dial tone ringing]
[Helene] Charlie's not my dad,
he's more like…
[Helene] Hi, I can't come
to the phone right now.
Please leave a message.
[voicemail beeping]
[Joachim] Hi, Helene. It's me.
I know you said you needed time,
but I've found something very important
that you really need to hear.
Call me as soon as you can.
-Thank you.
-[Edmund] Cheers.
Cheers.
You wanted to ask me something?
Yes, um…
Were…
Were we separating?
Sorry?
Before I went missing, um…
Was divorce something we discussed?
Uh, what makes you say that?
I just got this feeling. Like a flashback.
A flashback?
[Helene] Mm-hmm.
Okay? Pretty interesting.
[Edmund breathes deeply]
Mm… Were we divorcing?
No! No.
[Helene] No.
Okay.
No way.
Who is… Elisabeth Fauerskov?
Um… She was the director
at one of our sub-contractors.
Hm. And you knew her personally?
Yes, I knew her from back in school.
And do you know why she won't talk to me?
You've lost me.
She was one of the last people
I spoke to before I disappeared,
so I phoned her today and um…
She wouldn't talk to me at all.
She hung up, so…
Okay, but there's actually a…
a simple reason for that. Um…
We stopped working with them after…
they broke a trade-restraint clause,
so she's not allowed
to speak to you by law.
Oh.
My love…
Now please stop.
Don't embroil yourself with that again.
You'll get tangled in a web of delusions
that lead to nowhere.
-[scoffs] What?
-You're very upset.
[scoffs] No, I'm not upset at all.
Did we argue over her?
Alexander told me we were arguing
before I disappeared, and..
I thought perhaps we were arguing about
her and there was something going on?
It's all in your mind.
I mean, Helene, you sound paranoid.
I'm only asking a few questions here.
Okay.
[sighs]
[clears throat] I've tried saying it
as gently as possible, but I'll try again.
You are ill, Helene.
[exhales]
What are you trying to say?
You have a form of personality disorder,
like schizophrenia.
The doctors think
that maybe it's always been there…
And um, the abrupt death
of your father triggered you.
I am not schizophrenic.
-[Edmund] Look…
-No!
-So how do you explain it?
-Explain what?
Helene, you left your family.
You went to Norway. New name, new house.
You started a whole new life.
Yeah, yeah, Edmund I had amnesia.
[sighs]
Mm-hmm. From hitting your head?
-[Helene] Yes.
-Ah.
Then you woke up on a ship.
[distorted rumbling]
-Can you hear yourself?
-Yeah. [exhales]
[echoing] It's not really a sane person
who does that, is it?
I don't feel good. Um, I need air.
-Here. Um, sit down.
- Can we go outside?
-Take a breath. Breathe.
-No, I want…
-Try to calm down.
-No, I just want some fresh air.
I want some fresh air.
Will you please just--
-[grunts]
-[Helene yelps]
That's enough now!
[panicked breathing]
[Edmund] That's enough.
Helene, I won't accept…
that you decimate our family again.
[ominous music rises]
[Helene sobs]
It's okay. It's okay, it's okay…
[Edmund] Come on, let's go upstairs.
You need to rest.
[music intensifies]
[musik kulminerer]
[breathing deeply]
[doorbell ringing]
-Hi. You okay?
-[Joachim] Hi there. I'm Joachim.
-[Edmund] Joachim?
-Yes, uh, you know of me?
-Yes. I do.
-Right.
I just wanted to, um, speak to Helene.
[exhales]
Um…
Well, she's already gone to bed.
-Okay. She's asleep already?
-[Edmund] Mm-hmm. Yes.
Helene's gone through…
Well, quite a hard time.
Mm.
I'm… I'm sure she has.
So if you want to talk to her,
might be best to come back another time.
-Then I'll come back tomorrow to see her.
-I think she'll need more time than that.
I'll have her get back to you
as soon as possible. Okay?
But Joachim, um…
Since you're already here…
[chuckles softly]
Uh, actually,
I'd love to speak to you about something.
Have you got a minute?
-Of course.
-Come in. Hmm?
[Edmund] This is my mother, Caroline.
[Caroline] Good evening.
-Uh, let's go in here. Yeah?
-Sure.
[breathing echoes]
Joachim…
-Is, um, is that for her? That folder?
-[Joachim] Yeah.
-[Edmund] Mm-hmm.
-I've been trying to…
Well, just kind of work it out.
Yes. Of course.
Um, shall we look at it now, or--
No, I'll talk directly with Helene, so…
[exhales]
[Helene] Joachim…
[Edmund] Anything you'd like to ask me?
Since you've been putting in
all that effort to…
work it out, as you said.
I was wondering why
you didn't go public when she…
when she vanished. It's a bit… weird
We were convinced that
Helene had ended it all.
And I didn't want that
dragged through the press.
Particularly for Alexander's sake.
He's our son.
-And what about her father?
-[Edmund] What about him?
The news of his death,
you also kept that news so quiet…
-I would say.
-[Edmund] Yes, you're not wrong.
It really was an unworthy death
for a man of his calibre.
That's why we didn't go public with it.
[chuckles] It's… so… fascinating.
Fascinating?
Well how do you do it?
There's nothing about any of you online.
If you search, there's nothing.
It's like the whole family doesn't exist.
[banging]
[Helene groaning]
Uh, yes.
Um, there's a reason for that as well.
We had it erased.
We have a department
in the company that handles that.
[scoffs]
But why?
[Edmund] We don't think
the tragedies of the Söderberg family
should be a public spectacle.
[Helene grunts]
[Edmund] Joachim, I understand
that this is hard for you.
You've lost the woman that you love.
What I can say is that
Helene always hurts people, unfortunately.
Even if it's not her intention.
That's why I have a proposal.
[Helene, echoing] Joachim…
I gather you ran a café with her?
Which is now closed?
Because you can't run it alone.
I was also told that you've spent
several years working on a book too?
Hang on, uh…
[scoffs] I don't see how that's relevant,
to be honest with you…
Joachim, I'll be blunt.
I have money that can help you.
-[banging]
-[Helene grunting]
[Edmund] So I've had
an agreement drafted up. Um…
Which, financially speaking,
is quite lucrative for you.
CONFIDENTIALITY AGREEMENT
[Edmund] We'd like to ensure
that Helene's disappearance,
and the tragedy of our family
doesn't end up making it into a book
or any kind of colourful story, you see.
[banging]
[Edmund] You and I have been through
some tragic events.
But this has hurt Alexander most of all.
I've tried to shield him.
And I intend to keep it that way.
You can keep your hard-earned money,
'cause I'm gonna leave now.
[Joachim sighs]
Uh, tell me. Are you under the influence?
Perhaps you would like to sit down
for a little while.
I haven't been drinking.
-[ominous music playing]
-[Helene grunting]
You haven't had a drink?
No.
[Edmund] Okay.
[Helene mumbling]
I'm not judging you. It would be
completely fair and understandable
if you had felt the need
to have a drink today.
-Well, I haven't. I've been fine.
-No?
-Okay.
-[Joachim] Yeah.
Goodbye.
-You know your way out?
-[Joachim] Yeah.
[ominous music intensifies]
[music builds]
[loud clattering]
[panting]
[Helene] Joachim…
[footsteps approaching]
Helene, what's wrong?
Helene, come with me, darling.
Let's get you back to bed.
[Caroline] What are you saying?
[Helene] Edmund…
Edmund?
[Caroline, echoing] I know how he can be.
But you know, Helene?
After you vanished,
I'd not known him devastated like that.
He loves you so much.
You and Alexander are everything to him.
[Helene] Hi, I can't come to the phone
right now, please leave a message.
[sounds distort]
[normality resumes]
[sighs]
[gasps]
[indistinct chatter echoes]
[distorted rumbling]
[woman, echoes] Get away. I hate you!
Elisabeth?
[eerie music playing]
[music quickens]
[phone unlocks]
INBOX
I'VE TRIED CALLING YOU
SEVERAL TIMES.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
KIND REGARDS, ELISABETH
[Edmund breathes deeply]
Good morning.
-[Helene] Okay, so you go first.
-Mm.
-And no peeking. Mm.
-Uh-huh. Mm.
Coffee.
[Alexander humming happily]
[Edmund] I need to take a call,
and then we'll go.
It's your turn.
-Right, and so I draw… A body?
-A body. You start there.
[Helene] Okay.
[Edmund chattering on phone]
[Helene] Now it's your turn.
[Alexander humming happily]
[Edmund chattering indistinctly]
All finished.
Okay.
[children chattering]
[Helene] Have a great day. Mm.
And hey you, I love you. You are my life.
What's wrong?
It's just that's what you said
before you went away.
Alexander, I won't leave you again, okay?
I'll never leave you again. I swear.
Never.
Come here.
-Mm. See you later.
-[Alexander] See ya.
-[bell ringing]
-Go on, then.
Yeah. Have fun.
[Alexander] Bye.
DYSSEGÅRD SCHOOL
[ominous electronic music playing]
[Edmund] What's he doing here?
[sighs] I don't want you talking
to him any more.
It might set you back
and I don't want you stressed.
I know.
But he won't go away
until I've said goodbye to him properly.
I promise I'll end things with him,
for the sake of our family.
Open it.
[lock clicks]
Hi. I've been trying to reach you.
I stopped by the house.
Did he speak to you about it?
-There's so much you need to see.
-Joachim.
-Joachim, stop. Stop it.
-I think he's hiding something--
We can't about it. Not here.
[Joachim] Are you scared of him?
Helene, if he's hurt you…
-I swear, I'm going to storm over…
-You can't. Stop.
He has to think I'm finishing it.
Okay?
Please trust me.
[Joachim] This is where I'm staying.
If you can make it there, we can talk.
-Yeah.
-[Joachim] Okay.
-[Helene] Vi må sige farvel nu.
You're right. Things don't add up.
But I'm figuring it out, okay?
I love you.
[Helene breathing nervously]
[clears throat]
[indistinct chatter]
Yeah, okay.
[ominous electronic music playing]
Yes, see you tomorrow then. Take care.
Elisabeth, I need you to talk to me.
I'm not angry.
What?
Yeah, if you and Edmund are having
an affair and he dismissed you…
Look I have no idea what's going on,
but, um, I'm just looking for answers.
What are you talking about?
As if we're having an affair.
Then why won't you speak to me?
Because you lot forced me to sign a
legally-binding non-disclosure agreement!
Um. Wait, wait, stop, please.
Stop. Who did?
You know who did.
-Your husband.
-Hang on.
Okay. Um. Look, whatever…
I swear you can talk to me.
Yeah, I've heard it all before.
"You won't do anything."
I have no idea what you mean.
If we've talked already,
I don't remember it.
I don't remember it!
Just over two years ago, you contacted me.
And what I said then, is…
that I'd found out that one of our ships
was being used to commit crimes.
Serious stuff.
Buying women. Human trafficking.
Using your freight containers.
[sighs]
Okay. And how did you discover it?
I received emails from a woman
who said she had gathered some evidence.
You know, photos of the containers.
All the routes that were used.
Schedules.
She told me that it was systematic.
And it wouldn't be going on
if someone high up hadn't approved it.
She said she was working with the women
and she wanted to meet.
So she then gave me an address.
But before we could meet you contacted me.
You said
that you would take it from there.
Well, did we meet?
I don't know.
I never heard from you again.
And, well, I even thought that…
you were actually behind it.
It was a guess.
I tried to talk to Edmund.
I tried to contact him about it.
But he would just kill it.
Our contract was cancelled.
I was fired and forced to sign an NDA.
And I was even threatened
by one of Edmund's employees.
And I'm a single mum of two.
I couldn't risk it.
[Helene sighs]
That means they are still doing it.
Yes. I'd say you're right.
Do you still have her details
in your address book?
Yes. She told me to meet here.
-I think she worked there.
-Okay.
Promise me you'll be careful if
you're beginning to dig this all up again.
[Helene] I will.
And your contact, what was she called?
Louise.
Louise Andersen.
[intense music rises]
[electronic tense music playing]
NIGHTCLUB - GENTLEMENS CLUB
[lock clicks]
[dampened club music]
[woman] Hi.
[Helene] Hi there.
Can I help you?
I'm looking for Louise.
Sure, she won't be long. Go through.
["Something's Coming"
by The Regulators playing]
♪ What was that tapping
On your window pane ♪
♪ Started in the distance
But no sign of rain ♪
♪ Shadows moving along the street ♪
♪ You feel your heart skip another beat… ♪
-Louise?
-[Lulu] Close. My name's Lulu.
Do you want a drink? Champagne?
Uh, no.
I'm looking for a girl called Louise.
She worked here about two years ago.
Order the champagne.
Yeah. [clears throat] Okay.
A… A bottle of champagne, yeah.
♪ And it's coming ♪
♪ It's coming for you ♪
[distorted twinkling]
[indistinct voices echoing]
[champagne popping]
[classic rock music playing]
I hear you're looking for Louise?
Champagne.
Drink it.
Act like you're a normal customer.
-What do you want with her?
-[clears throat]
Did you know her?
Yeah.
We used to work together.
-Do you know where she is?
-No.
I haven't seen her in… Two, three years.
What happened to her?
There was night after work
she told me she wasn't coming back here.
Well, did she tell you why that was?
She was afraid.
[customers laughing]
[Louise's colleague] I don't know why.
Did she ever mention that she knew girls
who had been trafficked here?
[scoffs]
All of us could say the same.
Most girls here at least.
-[champagne popping]
-[woman yelps]
[scattered laughter and cheering]
Can I give you some advice?
You should be cautious.
People who ask questions like that
end up in trouble.
Wait, one last question.
Do… Do you know where she went?
Mm, she told me
she was leaving the country.
Something about going to Norway.
[tense music playing]
[music intensifies]
[music becomes chaotic]
[music fades out]
[Helene breathing shakily]
[door handle rattling]
[panicked breathing]
-[lock clicks open]
-[gasps softly]
[gaps]
[tense music playing]
[panting]
[Helene screaming]
[Helene] No! No! [straining]
[muffled screams]
[screaming subsides]
[mysterious music playing]
[doctor chats indistinctly]
[Edmund mutters indistinctly]
What?
Huh. You're awake.
Where am I?
Uh, slowly. Take it easy.
Yeah. Just relax.
[doctor] Helene, do you remember
how we discussed your medication?
Here you go.
You need to take two.
[læge] Mm.
Go ahead.
Mm.
Can I see? Open wide.
Helene, I've seen
every single trick in the book.
[doctor] Good.
[keypad beeping]
[electronic beeping]
[sighs] I had to.
I'm very sorry.
You just try and relax, okay?
[Edmund sighs]
Where's Alexander?
Well, he shouldn't see you like this.
[sighs]
What did you tell him?
[Edmund] I told him the truth.
I said that you're not well
and that you need rest.
He understood it.
-[scoffs]
-He's aware you're sick.
[shuddering]
I… I want to go home now.
-I want to go home to Alexander.
-I understand.
And we can do that.
But there's paperwork to deal with first.
APPOINTMENT OF GUARDIANSHIP
[Helene scoffs]
You… You want me under guardianship?
I'm trying to help.
I want you to have the best possible care.
[Helene scoffs]
[Edmund sighs]
Helene… I don't think you're listening.
This is for your own wellbeing. Hmm?
You can't run away again.
I know
what my father was trying to tell me.
[sighs]
[Helene] And I know who Louise is.
-You won't get away with this, Edmund.
-Oh, my love… [exhales]
You're seeing things you've imagined.
Things that aren't even real.
The pills will kick in soon. I've packed
some things for you to last a few days.
Try to get some rest.
I'll leave the papers here.
You can sign them when you feel better.
[sighs]
I love you.
[ominous music playing]
Soon you'll be your old self again.
[keypad beeping]
[dampened] Hello!
Hello!
Let me out! I need to see my son!
[retching]
[distorted twinkling]
[panting]
[suspenseful music playing]
We tried to escape.
[Louise echoes] Helene!
Helene! [panting] He's found us.
[foghorn blaring]
[Helene] There's a ship
I think we can make it if we jump.
What, have you gone crazy?
We can't do that.
[music intensifies]
Damn it!
[alarm ringing]
[alarm intensifies]
[Peter] Ah! Come here!
-[Helene straining]
-[Peter grunts]
[panting]
[Peter coughing]
[persistent knocking]
[knocking continues]
[Helene panting]
They're looking for me.
Is there any way they'd know this address?
-No, no, no.
-[Helene] Okay.
He has Alexander.
-I won't leave him there.
-[Joachim] We'll figure it out.
[Helene] I knew her.
Louise Andersen. I met her.
Okay?
I was in contact with her, and she…
had evidence.
Proof that Edmund was using the company
for trafficking.
All right. Uh, tell me the whole story.
She fled to Norway. Um…
-Louise?
-Yes. And I followed her, and…
We… We were on a bridge, and I…
There was a bridge?
[Joachim] Where is it? Oh… damn.
Er det den?
I've been thinking a lot about that ship
and trying to figure out
how you got onto it if you didn't board
as a passenger,
and it's crazy, but what if you jumped?
And if you take the ship routes
and heights into account…
then this was the only place.
[Helene] Give me your bag and run.
I'll stop him and speak to him.
-You can't! No way!
-You've done enough.
[Helene] Give me your bag.
Run. Go!
[suspenseful music playing]
[Helene] Stop!
Stop!
[exclaims erratically]
-[Louise screaming]
-[gasps]
[foghorn blaring]
[music intensifies]
-[Helene strains]
-[Edmund] Helene!
Helene…
[panting]
Don't do it.
[trembling]
[Edmund] Helene…
I beg you. Don't do it.
[music intensifies, halts]
It was Edmund.
He… He killed Louise.
And I saw it and then I… I jumped.
She gave me a…
-Look at that…
-[gasps]
[laughs softly]
-I kept it hidden.
-[Joachim] A little too hidden.
[doorbell ringing]
Hi.
-Helene?
-[Helene] I need your help.
Found it.
What do we think we'll find on it?
[clears throat]
Beviser af en slags.
[inhales, exhales]
My goodness. What is it?
Trafficking.
[inhales sharply] In our containers?
Yes. Edmund used my father's business.
So everything
that Elisabeth said was right.
[Helene] Yes.
And then Edmund tried bury the evidence
-[Ingrid] No.
-Hvad er der?
That ship…
[Ingrid] We've been working with
the firm that owns that ship
for a long time.
From before Edmund joined the company.
Since when?
[Ingrid] Over 50 years.
Weren't these the pages
that were torn from my book?
Uh, yes, I think so.
[Ingrid] Helene, I have to tell you…
JM Shipping…
These were some of our partnerships
that your father handled.
He didn't want me to get involved in it.
[distorted rumbling]
CO-OPERATION FOR LIFE
AKSEL SÖDERBERG
WITH J. M. SHIPPING
[Ingrid] Edmund is probably involved
as well. It all points to that, but…
I'd say it started long before
he joined the firm, and there's no doubt.
So, my father started it?
Yeah.
So that's what he was trying to say…
Before he died,
he tried to confess, and warn me.
[Aksel] Edmund…
So, what now?
-I need to get Alexander.
-
I must confront Edmund.
Yes, but Edmund is evil.
There's nothing he can do!
I have evidence.
So take that evidence to the police
so we can get out of this.
But we can't wait
for the police to look at it, Joachim.
They'll take months,
and he has a million lawyers,
and he can talk his way out of everything.
And yes, he is evil.
That's why I have to rescue Alexander.
[Caroline] "Should I leave the road
or go into the woods alone
when my mother has forbidden it."
[classical music playing]
-Mm?
-[Alexander] Grandma?
-Is Mum coming home?
Yes, I'm sure she'll soon be home again.
Don't you worry, darling.
Sleep tight. Good night.
-[Caroline] Goodnight.
-[Alexander] Goodnight.
She'll come home again.
Okay.
[Caroline] I'm going to bed.
[electronic suspenseful music playing]
Come and find me
if I'm not back in ten minutes.
Be safe.
Great to have you home again.
Would you like some wine?
I know what you and my father were doing.
I have proof now.
It's hidden in a safe place.
Alexander comes with me.
Let us go, and it stays hidden.
But we are leaving you.
And you have to let us.
Helene, you do not have a clue
what this is about.
[Edmund sighs] I can't let you go.
In fact, I won't allow you
to disappear again.
Allow me to?
You let me disappear.
And you ensured that they found me again.
Okay.
It might be for the best if I explain
exactly what happened…
But afterwards,
I think you'll want to stay with me.
[inhales] You're right.
[Edmund] You discovered
the company's involvement in trafficking
two years ago.
I wanted to stop you.
However, I couldn't stop you in time.
You got away.
At first, I thought you'd died in Norway.
But then I discovered
you started an entirely new life.
I had a hard time believing
the story about amnesia.
[sighs] But in the end it was true.
Or was it?
Were you watching me?
[Edmund chuckles softly] Yeah.
Of course I was.
It became almost like an obsession.
And yet it really pained me…
to see you…
with him.
[ominous music playing]
[Edmund] It wasn't easy for me
to see you living a life without me.
But I handled it.
Well, until it got too much for me.
I couldn't take seeing you
engaged to another man.
So I had to bring you home again.
Helene…
You're mine.
[knives slinking]
We belong together.
[breathing nervously]
[Edmund]I knew that bringing you home
was a big risk.
It was a gamble to trust that
you wouldn't regain your memories,
which was, of course, naive.
You let our son live
without his mother for two years.
But I did let you live, Helene.
[inhales sharply]
What about Louise?
You didn't let her live.
-No.
-You killed her.
-She was ruining what we had.
-[scoffs] You're insane.
I love you.
I love you more than anything
in this world.
[grunts] I'm going to get Alexander.
And you'll let us go.
-No.
-[Helene] Yes, you will.
-You're going to, I have evidence!
The proof you have
mainly implicates your father,
and he's not here to contest it.
So then who takes the fall? Our company.
And our company, my love…
That's you and me.
Hi, Ingrid.
I wanted to ask you about something.
That book you showed us
with old employees?
-[Ingrid] yes?
-In the photo from 1976.
There's a tall blonde lady in the line.
She looks familiar.
If you go to the police,
I'll take you down with me.
So how about we just sort this out
as a family?
-Don't come near me.
-Don't shout, you'll wake Alexander up.
The woman on the left.
That's Caroline, Edmund's mother.
Mother, can you sort her out?
[Helene choking]
[Helene falls to the floor]
And did she work at the company?
Yes. She was Aksel Söderberg's secretary
before me.
[electronic suspenseful music playing]
[Helene breathing heavily]
[woman] You can't treat me like this!
[Aksel] Come back !
Don't you walk away from me!
-Get off me! Get away! I hate you!
-[Aksel] Hey! Wait!
This is what happens
when you treat me like this.
Stop this. Caroline!
[Helene slurs] It was you.
You were here, when I was little.
Get her upstairs or she'll wake Alexander.
-[Helene moaning softly]
-[Caroline] Put her on the bed.
-Let go.
-Easy.
-[panicked breathing]
-[Edmund] Easy, easy, easy.
Okay. Okay.
Why were you here back then?
You said you didn't know my father well.
Helene, your father was a bad man.
What are you talking about?
For eight years, I looked after him.
I loved him. Worshipped him.
He said he loved me as well.
He promised we'd get married.
But as soon as he met your mother,
he broke it off with me for her.
He cast me out.
I wasn't good enough any longer.
-[dispatcher] What's your emergency?
-Hi. I think I need some help here.
-What's your location?
-Could you send the police to, uh…
-Lindevej 12.
-Yes, of course.
Can you tell me what this is about?
[Peter and Joachim grunting]
He underestimated mother
and how much she knew about his secrets.
I had to make sure
Edmund had a future at Söderberg
We deserved it.
So I forced Aksel to hire Edmund.
But Helene, you have to believe me.
Our love…
It was always real.
[both grunting]
You two are sick.
You see? I told you she'd react this way.
She just needs a bit more time.
Last time you let her live
you saw what happened!
You know she has to die,
just like her father.
So that everything
we've fought for isn't ruined.
Dad? [panting] Dad? Dad? Dad?
[panting] You killed my father
to stop him confessing?
Remarkable how you find your morality
when close to death, wouldn't you say?
[both grunting]
You're going to have to finish it.
-I'll get her to come around.
-[Caroline] No, Edmund!
You insisted on bringing Helene home
and I let you, but it didn't work, okay?
So this stops here!
[Edmund] Mother!
[Helene breathing shakily]
It is my decision.
[inhales angrily] You're pathetic.
This is pathetic. She doesn't want you,
don't you see that?
Don't you see that?
Fine, I'll do it.
[Helene struggling]
Stop! Stop! Mother, stop it! Stop it now!
Stop! Stop, hey!
She's still Alexander's mother!
[Edmund grunts]
-No!
-[Caroline screams]
-[body thuds]
-[gaps]
No. No…
[panting]
Mother… Mother…
[Edmund] No. No.
[sighs]
[breathing heavily]
[tense music rises]
[music steadies]
-[door thuds]
-[Edmund] Mother! Mother!
[softly] Mother… No. No.
[sobbing]
[sirens whirring]
[mysterious music playing]
[indistinct police radio]
[mysterious music swells]
[music steadies, softens]
[police officer over radio] Traffic police
have been notified.
An ambulance is on the way
to the crime scene, ETA 20 minutes.
[radio continues indistinctly]
[bright music playing]
Yes, it is!
You see? See that white house there?
-Yeah.
-With the swimming pier? You see it?
Will we live there?
[Helene] If you'd like to.
-[Alexander] Come on, Mummy!
-[Helene] Whoo!
-[Joachim] Here she comes!
-[Alexander] Yeah.
[Helene] Oh, it's cold!
[boys chattering indistinctly]
-[Joachim] I'm gonna spin you. Go on.
-[Alexander] All right.
-[Alexander chuckles]
-Here we go!
[both chuckle]
-Ah!
-[both chuckle]
[Alexander] Okay, again! Come on!
[Joachim] Throw it to me over there
and then I'll swim over.
[Alexander] Great. You gonna swim under?
[Joachim] Yeah I'll swim under,
and then I'll come back to you, okay?
Throw it to me.
-[Alexander] Oh!
-[Joachim] Okay, are you ready?
[Alexander] Yeah.
-[Joachim] Okay. Three, two, one. Throw!
-[Alexander grunts]
[Joachim laughs] No, further than that!
Hey, Mum, it's really great here!
[exhales] You always did like swimming.
Can you remember now?
[Helene] A few things, yes.
[dramatic flourish]
["Running Away" by Hoffman,
Estrada og Franklin playing]